For the IoT platform installation.
We're going to use a remote Linux server that we have rented in a cloud provider.
For this example, the server name will be: iot-app.univ-lorawan.fr.
If you don't have a remote server or a domain name, then don't worry.
You can do it on your own machine if you want.
We've prepared everything.
The only thing you need to do is to download the configuration code from our GitHub repository.
Git clone the repository called LoRaWAN.
The configuration is in a file called Docker-compose.yml in the folder LoRaWAN/application/IoT-app
...
If you look at this Docker-compose.yml  file, then you can see the three services Node-RED, influxdb
and Grafana.
Obviously if you already have a Node-RED instance running because you installed it earlier in this course,
then you have to command the Node-RED part using the # symbol.
Otherwise you can stop your active Node-RED container and start everything over.
Anyway, we're going to give the explanation from a fresh installation, so we'll build everything from
the ground up.
Let's see in detail what we have prepared for these three services.
For Node-RED we've used the default Node-RED container, but we added the dashboard library, so we'll
be able to create dashboard in Node-RED if you don't want to use Grafana.
We also added a basic authentication to access the Node-RED web page with a login and password.
The login is "admin" and the password is "univ-lorawan."
For influxdb, there is also a username and a password to access the database.
Again, it's "admin" for the username and "univ-lorawan" for the password.
You can easily change it here if you want.
For influxdb.
We'll also see later that we need to provide the name of an organization, a bucket and a token.
You can choose your own value here so that it will be applied during the container creation.
If you don't provide these values, then it doesn't matter.
You will be able to create them from the user interface later.
And finally, to enter the Grafana user interface on Port 3000, we'll need the same username and password.
And again, you can see that you can change it here.
Great.
So you can use the default value from this file and use it exactly as you've downloaded it without modifying
anything.
But be careful.
Please check this configuration when you download the repository from GitHub because there might be
little changes or updates on this file.
When we're happy with the configuration, then we just need to use the command "sudo docker compose up -d"
...
All images are downloaded, containers are created and after a few seconds everything is up and running.
As usual, we can check the running services with the command "sudo docker ps" and there we go.
We have all the information on Node-RED, influxdb and Grafana.